<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Luis Nova's Blog</title><link>/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Luis Nova's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GPS technology</title><link>/post/gps-technology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/gps-technology/</guid><description>You can find GPS systems in your car, your smartphone and your watch. GPS helps you get where you are going, from point A to point B.
##What is GPS and how does it work?
The Global Positioning System (GPS) is a navigation system using satellites, a receiver and algorithms to synchronize location, velocity and time data for air, sea and land travel.
While we only need three satellites to produce a location on earth’s surface, a fourth satellite is often used to validate the information from the other three.</description></item><item><title>Smart Restaurants</title><link>/post/smart-restaurants/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/smart-restaurants/</guid><description>Service robots These robots are autonomously operated by an internal control system with the option to manually override the operation. The International Organization for Standardization defines a “service robot” as a robot “that performs useful tasks for humans.”
Smart table A table or surface which is able to display some content and allows for user input by means of some interaction paradigm.
Features Unlimited Multi-Touch surface</description></item><item><title>Stock Market</title><link>/post/stock-market/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/stock-market/</guid><description>What is Stock market? Stock market helps you trade financial instruments like bonds, mutual funds, derivatives as well as shares of companies.
The key factor is the stock exchange – the basic platform that provides the facilities used to trade company stocks and other securities. A stock may be bought or sold only if it is listed on an exchange. Thus, it is the meeting place of the stock buyers and sellers.</description></item><item><title>Mark V-A1</title><link>/post/markv-a1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/markv-a1/</guid><description>Mark V-A1
MarkV-A1 or Mark5-A1 is a bomb disposal robot designed for the purpose of handling potential explosives without risking any lives.
Description:
The ANDROS MARK V-A1 is the largest, strongest, robot in the REMOTEC family. Its 3.5-mph speed, coupled with its unique articulated tracks allows the ANDROS MARK V-A1 to rapidly maneuver over rough terrain and obstacles, climb stairs, and cross ditches as wide as 24 inches. The vehicle is environmentally sealed to operate in any weather condition and in areas of high temperature/humidity.</description></item><item><title>Cenotaph</title><link>/post/cenotaph/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/cenotaph/</guid><description>A cenotaph is an empty tomb or a monument erected in honour of a person or group of people whose remains are elsewhere. It can also be the initial tomb for a person who has since been reinterred elsewhere. Although the vast majority of cenotaphs honour individuals, many noted cenotaphs are instead dedicated to the memories of groups of individuals, such as the lost soldiers of a country or of an empire.</description></item><item><title>Drone racing</title><link>/post/drone-racing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/drone-racing/</guid><description>PV drone racing (where FPV stands for first-person view or first person video) is a sportypically small radio-controlled aircraft or quadcopters), equipped with cameras while wearing head-mounted displays showing the live stream camera feed from the drones. Similar to full size air racing, the goal is to complete a set course as quickly as possible.
FPV (first person view) flying means that pilots only see what the drone sees.</description></item><item><title>London Location</title><link>/post/cancer-survivors-garden/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/cancer-survivors-garden/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The cancer experience is a test of endurance and unfortunately the focus is on the people who succumb to the disease but not on the overwhelming numbers that survive. One of the things I found was important to me was to mark the ending of my treatment in a way that was significant, to celebrate the end of my treatment. It was like crossing a finish line.&amp;rdquo; ~ Mary Coulter ~</description></item><item><title>Drone technology</title><link>/post/drone/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/drone/</guid><description>Unmanned aircraft. &amp;hellip; Essentially, a drone is a flying robot that can be remotely controlled or fly autonomously through software-controlled flight plans in their embedded systems, working in conjunction with onboard sensors and GPS
Industry role:
Due to the implementation of this device in different fields such as domiciles, video and photography. The drone has played an important role in large companies as it has become a fundamental part of each company due to its ease of use and the benefits provided by its use.</description></item><item><title>Guide dogs</title><link>/post/5g/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/5g/</guid><description>The product replicates the role of a guide dog as well as programming quick and safe routes to destinations using real-time data.
It is all smart and simple
The design are basically channels the functions of a guide dog into a robotic device that can be held in hand. While it is still in prototype form, Theia will be able to help visually impaired users to go their way once a few kinks are ironed out.</description></item><item><title>Bionic prosthetics</title><link>/post/my-third-post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/my-third-post/</guid><description>Bionic Engineering is known as the one specialized in the production of technological tools that simulate the functioning or model of living beings. Its objective is the combination of electronic and biological systems, enhancing its advantages and characteristics. examples of this are: BIONIC HAND PROSTHESIS It is usually made of polyurethane that guarantees stability and lightweight. It is important that to achieve almost natural replacement of the lost hand, the user should receive the noticeable sensations that he perceives when grasping or manipulate an object.</description></item><item><title>Why it's a great opportunity to invest?</title><link>/post/my-second-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/my-second-post/</guid><description>Due to the globalization society has undergone constant changes, especially in the digital area. So far the 21st century has seen a great rise in the market. , Where the internet has been one of the greatest exponents of these changes, thanks to this today it is possible to invest digitally.
One of the main digital investment methods is: the purchase and sale of shares of multinational companies, which is better known as the stock market.</description></item><item><title>Da Vinci Robot</title><link>/post/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/my-first-post/</guid><description>This device was developed by the North American company Intuitive Surgical and approved in 2000 by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) of the United States. It is used for multiple surgical procedures, including prostatectomies and vaginal hysterectomy. The da Vinci robot is not autonomous; in all cases requires the intervention and decision-making of a professional who acts as a human operator for all actions. components:
-Ergonomic console from which the surgeon operates seated and which normally, is in the same operating room.</description></item><item><title/><link>/post/nano-robots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/nano-robots/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/post/wireless-technology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/wireless-technology/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>